Preliminary Guide to the French WWI Prisoner of War Camp Newspapers, 1914-1918
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
French WWI Prisoner of War Camp Newspapers 1914-1918
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Duke University. David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library.
11 items 0.4 linear feet
Newspapers for French prisoners of war held throughout Europe during World War I.
Newspapers were intended for French prisoners of war during World War I, and were collected from a variety of different POW camps in Europe. This collection contains examples of 11 single issues, each from a different camp. Locations include the Camp D'Ohrdruf, Camps du Hanovre, Allemagne, Camp de Zossen, and others.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
Transfer, 2007 (2007-0197), 0.4 lin. ft.
Biographical / Historical Note
Newspapers for French prisoners of war held throughout Europe during World War I.
Collection Overview
Newspapers intended for French prisoners of war during World War I, collected from a variety of different POW camps in Europe. This collection contains examples of 11 single issues, each from a different camp. Locations include the Camp D'Ohrdruf, Camps du Hanovre, Allemagne, Camp de Zossen, and others.
Subject Headings
These and related materials may be found under the following headings in online catalogs.
World War, 1914-1918 -- Prisoners and prisons -- France
World War, 1914-1918 -- Prisoners and prisons -- Germany
Prisoner-of-war camps
Prisoners of war
Newspapers
Contents of Collection
- French WWI Prisoner of War Camp Newspapers, 1914-1918, 1 Folder
  The history and provenance of these materials are unknown. They were transferred to the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library from Perkins Library in 2007. No additional arrangement or organization has been conducted at this point.
  - Les Camps du Hanovre, 1915
  - Bulletin Paroissial du Camp d'Ohrdruf, 1915 May 16
  - Le Camp de Göttingen, 1915 Apr. 4
  - L'Intermède, Camp de Würzburg, 1917 Nov. 10
  - Le Hèraut, Echos du Camp de Zossen, 1914 Oct. 18
  - Bulletin pour les Prisonniers français en Allemagne, 1914 Oct.
  - Bulletin Organe Hebdomadaire, 1915 Jan. 23
  - Le Journal du Camp d'Ohrdruf, 1916 Jan. 23
  - Le Messager du Prisonnier du Guerre
  - Nouvelles Hebdomadaires, Cologne, 1915 Mar. 16
  - Nouvelles Hebdomadaires, Cologne, 1915 Jun. 22